# Sergio Laguardia

Software Engineer San Francisco. CA

SergioLaguardia.com · (415) 535-2141

sergioslaguardia@gmail.com · in/sergiolaguardia · github.com/selaguardia

As a software engineer with a degree in business and experience in customer service, I bring my business knowledge and apply it to all of my coding projects. I naturally get excited and passionate about visualizing and creating apps from the ground up and seeing them come to life. I specialize in full-stack JavaScript technologies (MERN stack: MongoDB, Express JS, React JS, Node JS) to build complete web applications with API systems.

# **SKILLS**

Languages - JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Python, SQL, Mongo, JSON, Typescript, EJS, DTL

Database - PostgreSQL, MongoDB

**Libraries and Frameworks -** React (class-based and hooks), Express.js, Django, jQuery, Bootstrap, Bulma **Other -** RESTful Routing, JSON API

# SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

\_Aug 2020 - Present

Restaurant Overhaul | Revamped a businesses website adding

- Full-stack web application utilizing a MEN stack (MongoDB, Express, Node.js)
- Utilized JavaScript, EJS templating for views, and Bootstrap for styling.

<u>Project Wayfarer</u> | A web application where people can share tips about their favorite street art around the world.

- Full-stack web application utilizing **Python**, **Django**, **PostgreSQL**, Bootstrap, Heroku, and **GitHub** for version control.
- Full CRUD (create, read, update, delete) capabilities.

instaBump | An Instagram clone to upload and share photos.

- Reverse engineered a full-stack web application utilizing a MEN stack (MongoDB, Express, Node.js) to build a full-stack application in a 1-week sprint.
- With full create, read, update, delete (CRUD) operations hitting all RESTful API calls.
- Created front-end application with a web-first approach utilizing **HTML**, **CSS**, **JavaScript**, and **jQuery** for DOM manipulation.

### **Project Zero** | My first simple game app.

- Built a front-end web application that users can see and interact with
- Utilized HTML, CSS, JavaScript, APIs, ¡Query, GitHub

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# University of Calfornia, San Francisco | Intern

Aug 2019 - June 2020

• Interned for hospital research team called DeLIVER Care by creating schedules and also marketing material for the services they offer by using the latest technologies, iPad Pro and Canvas app.

#### Uber, Driver | San Francisco, CA

May 2013 - Mar 2020

- Achieved Top Driver status by having a 4.96 rating while completing 6,600+ rides.
- Transported 15-30 clients daily to and from their destinations; demonstrated flexibility and patience dealing with unexpected traffic and passenger issues.
- Generated an Excel spreadsheet to monitor and track mileage, maintenance, and miscellaneous expenses for tax purposes.

#### Mechanics Bank, Customer Service Representative / Teller | Oakland, CA

Jan 2017 - Sep 2017

 Assisted over 50 clients a day processing check orders, balancing their accounts, opening safe deposit boxes, and processing transactions following established procedures and security guidelines. Communicated professionally and discreetly.

- Protected the bank's assets by ensuring sufficient funds in accounts, including processing stop payments.
- Implemented a new filing system and reorganized the office to allow for more efficient use of our time.

### Target, Guest Service Team Member | Pinole, CA

Sept 2011 - Aug 2013

- Awarded Employee of the Month and Cashier of Month (3x) within the first year based on being trained in multiple departments and consistently exceeding sales targets.
- Selected to be cross-trained in multiple departments, including customer service, cashier, sales floor Target cafe, and electronics; resulting in being entrusted with covering managers' breaks and lunches.

# **EDUCATION**

# General Assembly | Remote

Software Engineering Immersive

June 2021 - Sep 2021

Full-stack software engineering immersive student in an intensive, twelve-week, 450+ hour program focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and team collaboration strategies. Developed a portfolio of individual and group projects.

### San Francisco State University | San Francisco, CA

Bachelor of Science in Business Administration, concentration in Information Systems

Aug 2020

- Dean's List (2x)
- SAP Recognition Award
- Mendix Rapid Developer Certificate

University of California, Davis | Davis, CA June 2017

Managerial Economics General Ed

Diablo Valley College | Pleasant Hill, CA

Associate's Degree in Political Science

May 2015